University of Connecticut
© 2004 University of Connecticut
University of Connecticut, School of Pharmacy Records.
undated, 1925-
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut School of Pharmacy.
9.5 linear feet
MSS19930077
The Connecticut College of Pharmacy was established in 1925 in New Haven, Connecticut. In 1941, the Connecticut General Assembly enacted legislation to incorporate the College as part of the University of Connecticut. The collection contains an extensive collection of clippings (scrapbooks) concerning the program and its faculty, students and graduates in addition to historical papers, documents and reports about pharmacy and the program at the University.
History
The Connecticut College of Pharmacy was established in 1925 and located in New Haven, Connecticut. The first Dean of the College was Dr. Gustavus Eliot (1925-1928) who was followed by Dr. Henry S. Johnson (acting 1928-1930, 1930-1947). Under Dr. Johnson, the course in pharmacy was extended from two to three years (1927) and to four years in 1932 (B.S. degree). 1935 Connecticut College of Pharmacy was elected to membership in the American Association of Colleges of Pharmacy. In 1941, the Connecticut General Assembly incorporated the College as a School of the University of Connecticut. Beginning in 1942 diplomas were awarded in Storrs rather than in independent ceremonies at Sprague Hall (Yale University) as had been the practice to date. Dr. Harold Hewitt was appointed Dean in 1947, a position he held until his retirement in 1969. In 1951, the School moved to the Storrs Campus of the University. Subsequent Deans include Dr. Arthur E. Schwarting (1971-1981), Dr. Karl A. Nieforth (1982-1993), Dr. Michael Gerald (1993-2001), and Dr. Robert McCarthy (interim 2001-2003, 2003-).
In May 2001, the School of pharmacy broke ground for a new $61 million facility on the Storrs Campus. Construction began on the facility in 2002 and the building is schedule to open in Summer 2005. That same year, the University awarded its first Doctor of Pharmacy (Pharm.D.) degrees.
Additional information on the School, its programs and faculty is available from the School of Pharmacy's webpage or in The road to excellence: the University of Connecticut School of Pharmacy, 1925-2000 edited by Karl A. Nieforth.
Scope and Content
The collection contains random administrative records, reports, papers and speeches as well as an extensive collection of clippings (scrapbooks) documenting the establishment, activities, programs and individuals associated with the University of Connecticut School of Pharmacy and its predecessor, the Connecticut College of Pharmacy.
Arrangement
Series I: Subject Files ( undated, 1925- present )
Series II: Scrapbooks ( 1925-1969 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University's history. Additional materials relevant to the School of Pharmacy and its predecessor can be found in the University Photograph Collection, the Dodd Monograph Collection (books about pharmacy and UConn programs) and Dodd Periodicals (Faculty minutes, newsletters, and commencement programs). For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Organizations:
Connecticut College of Pharmacy.
Subjects:
University of Connecticut. School of Pharmacy.; Pharmacy colleges--Connecticut; Pharmacy--Study and teaching (Higher)--Connecticut.
Document Types:
Publications.; Administrative Records.; Fliers. [printed matter]; Photocopies.; Speeches.; Obituaries.; Bylaws.; Histories.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The materials in the collection were collected by Archives & Special Collections staff, transferred by the School of Pharmacy over time or donated to Archives & Special Collections by alumni.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Subject Files, undated, 1925-
  - Alumni, undated, 1975-1980 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Announcements/Brochures, undated, 1925, ca. 2002- (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Article: Harold Hewitt, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Article: Henry S. Johnson, 1931 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Building, 1951 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - By-Laws, Student Council, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Clinic, 1940 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - College of Pharmacy history, 1949-1950, 1958 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Dean: Speeches and reports, 1939, 1944 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Fenney, Nicholas certificate, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Guest Book, 1945 (Box 1:, Folder 11-12)
  - Guest Night, 1932-1934 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - History of pharmacy, undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Participating certificate, 1924 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Retirements, 2004 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
- Series II: Scrapbooks, 1925-1969
  - 1925-1927 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 1)
  - 1925-1959 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 2)
  - 1931-1937 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 3)
  - 1941-1944 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 4)
  - 1944-1947 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 5)
  - 1946-1950 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 6)
  - 1952-1959 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 7)
  - 1960-1964 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 8)
  - 1965-1969 (Box 1993-0077_, Folder 9)